<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>ameya.karkal</title>
    <link>https://ameyakarkal.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ameya.karkal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ameyakarkal.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>💡 insight</title>
      <link>https://ameyakarkal.github.io/projects/insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ameyakarkal.github.io/projects/insight/</guid>
      <description>azure-data-factory azure-kubernetes-services azure-functions dotnet-core node elasticsearch kanban OKRs azure-devops
Insight is an analytics product that provides a platform to consume data contributed by multiple products at Anthology Inc
Role Led initiative to architect and develop configuration driven ETL for analytics product Played key role in an endeavour for cross team data initiative Promoted approach for developing solutions based on iterative experiments rather than hypothesis Working in a team that uses kanban approach to achieve set Objectives measured by Key Results (OKRs) Contributions Led design and implementation for AKS based services for indexing data in elastic search clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>me</title>
      <link>https://ameyakarkal.github.io/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ameyakarkal.github.io/me/</guid>
      <description>Staff Product Developer 2019 to present
Led initiative to architect and develop configuration driven ETL for analytics product Played key role in an endeavour for cross team data initiative Promoted approach for developing solutions based on iterative experiments rather than hypothesis Working in a team that uses kanban approach to achieve set Objectives measured by Key Results (OKRs) Contributions:
Hands on experience with developing and deploying solutions on top of Azure Kubernetes Services Implemented cloud native data delivery pipelines using Azure Data Factory, Azure Functions and Azure Datalake Analytics Hands on experience with Azure DevOps and Infrastructure as Code primarily using Terraform Tech Stack :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🗳️ course evaluations</title>
      <link>https://ameyakarkal.github.io/projects/ce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ameyakarkal.github.io/projects/ce/</guid>
      <description>Course Evaluations is a Web based tool that caters to student facing survey, administrator facing reporting suite for higher education campuses.
entity-framework azure-webapps azure-devops azure-functions dotnet-core
Senior Software Developer
:key: Key Contributions Team was responsible for architecting and delivering high volume, business critical mass mailing solutions using azure&amp;rsquo;s serverless functions. The initiative improved Service Level Agreement and end-to-end visibility for all stakeholders I was involved in revamping legacy reporting microservice using Azure Data Factory and Azure Datalake Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
